<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>– Solutions to Common Problems</title><link>/docs/troubleshooting-guide/solutions-to-common-problems/</link><description>Recent content in Solutions to Common Problems on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/docs/troubleshooting-guide/solutions-to-common-problems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Boot in Emergency Mode</title><link>/docs/troubleshooting-guide/solutions-to-common-problems/boot-in-emergency-mode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/troubleshooting-guide/solutions-to-common-problems/boot-in-emergency-mode/</guid><description>
&lt;p>If you encounter problems during normal boot, you can boot in Emergency Mode.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perform the following steps to boot in Emergency Mode:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Restart the Photon OS machine or the virtual machine running Photon OS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When the Photon OS splash screen appears, as it restarts, type the letter &lt;code>e&lt;/code> quickly.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Append &lt;code>emergency&lt;/code> to the kernel command line.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Press &lt;code>F10&lt;/code> to proceed with the boot.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>At the command prompt, provide the root password to log in to Emergency Mode.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By default, &lt;code>/&lt;/code> is mounted as read-only.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To make modifications, run the following command to remount with write access:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>mount -o remount,rw /&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Docs: Resetting a Lost Root Password</title><link>/docs/troubleshooting-guide/solutions-to-common-problems/resetting-a-lost-root-password/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/troubleshooting-guide/solutions-to-common-problems/resetting-a-lost-root-password/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Perform the following steps to rest a lost password:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Restart the Photon OS machine or the virtual machine running Photon OS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When the Photon OS splash screen appears as it restarts, type the letter &lt;code>e&lt;/code> to go to the GNU GRUB edit menu quickly. Because Photon OS reboots so quickly, you won&amp;rsquo;t have much time to type &lt;code>e&lt;/code>. Remember that in vSphere and Workstation, you might have to give the console focus by clicking in its window before it will register input from the keyboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Second, in the GNU GRUB edit menu, go to the end of the line that starts with &lt;code>linux&lt;/code>, add a space, and then add the following code exactly as it appears below:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>rw init=/bin/bash
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>After you add this code, the GNU GRUB edit menu should look exactly like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="images/grub-edit-menu-changepw.png" alt="The modified GNU GRUB edit menu">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now type &lt;code>F10&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the command prompt, type &lt;code>passwd&lt;/code> and then type (and re-enter) a new root password that conforms to the password complexity rules of Photon OS. Remember the password.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next, type the following command:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>umount /
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Finally, type the following command. You must include the &lt;code>-f&lt;/code> option to force a reboot; otherwise, the kernel enters a state of panic.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>reboot -f
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>This sequence of commands should look like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="images/resetpw.png" alt="The series of commands to reset the root password">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the Photon OS machine reboots, log in with the new root password.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resetting-the-failed-logon-count">Resetting the failed logon count&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Resetting the root password will not reset the failed logon count, if you&amp;rsquo;ve had to many failed attempts, you may not be able to logon after resetting the password.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You will know if this is the case, if you see &lt;code>Account locked due to X failed logins&lt;/code> at the photon console.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To reset the count, before you unmount the filesystem, run the following&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>/sbin/pam_tally2 --reset --user root
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre></description></item><item><title>Docs: Fixing Permissions on Network Config Files</title><link>/docs/troubleshooting-guide/solutions-to-common-problems/fixing-permissions-on-network-config-files/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/troubleshooting-guide/solutions-to-common-problems/fixing-permissions-on-network-config-files/</guid><description>
&lt;p>When you create a new network configuration file as root user, the network service might be unable to process it until you set the file mode bits to &lt;code>644&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you query the journal with &lt;code>journalctl -u systemd-networkd&lt;/code>, you might see the following error message along with an indication that the network service did not start:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>`could not load configuration files. permission denied`
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>The permissions on the network files might cause this problem. Without the correct permissions, &lt;code>networkd-systemd&lt;/code> cannot parse and apply the settings, and the network configuration that you created will not be loaded.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After you create a network configuration file with a &lt;code>.network&lt;/code> extension, you must run the &lt;code>chmod&lt;/code> command to set the new file&amp;rsquo;s mode bits to &lt;code>644&lt;/code>. Example:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>`chmod 644 10-static-en.network`
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>For Photon OS to apply the new configuration, you must restart the &lt;code>systemd-networkd&lt;/code> service by running the following command:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>`systemctl restart systemd-networkd`
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre></description></item><item><title>Docs: Permitting Root Login with SSH</title><link>/docs/troubleshooting-guide/solutions-to-common-problems/permitting-root-login-with-ssh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/troubleshooting-guide/solutions-to-common-problems/permitting-root-login-with-ssh/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The full version of Photon OS prevents root login with SSH by default. To permit root login over SSH, open &lt;code>/etc/ssh/sshd_config&lt;/code> with the vim text editor and set &lt;code>PermitRootLogin&lt;/code> to &lt;code>yes&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vim is the default text editor available in both the full and minimal versions of Photon OS. The full version also contains Nano. After you modify the SSH daemon&amp;rsquo;s configuration file, you must restart the sshd daemon for the changes to take effect. Example:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>vim /etc/ssh/sshd_config
# override default of no subsystems
Subsystem sftp /usr/libexec/sftp-server
# Example of overriding settings on a per-user basis
#Match User anoncvs
# X11Forwarding no
# AllowTcpForwarding no
# PermitTTY no
# ForceCommand cvs server
PermitRootLogin yes
UsePAM yes
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Save your changes in vim and then restart the sshd daemon:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>systemctl restart sshd
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>You can then connect to the Photon OS machine with the root account over SSH:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>steve@ubuntu:~$ ssh root@198.51.100.131
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre></description></item><item><title>Docs: Fixing Sendmail</title><link>/docs/troubleshooting-guide/solutions-to-common-problems/fixing-sendmail/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/troubleshooting-guide/solutions-to-common-problems/fixing-sendmail/</guid><description>
&lt;p>If Sendmail is not behaving as expected or hangs during installation, it might be because FQDN is not set.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perform the following steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Set an FQDN for your Photon OS machine.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Run the following commands in the order below:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>echo $(hostname -f) &amp;gt; /etc/mail/local-host-names
cat &amp;gt; /etc/mail/aliases &amp;lt;&amp;lt; &amp;quot;EOF&amp;quot;
postmaster: root
MAILER-DAEMON: root
EOF
/bin/newaliases
cd /etc/mail
m4 m4/cf.m4 sendmail.mc &amp;gt; sendmail.cf
chmod 700 /var/spool/clientmqueue
chown smmsp:smmsp /var/spool/clientmqueue
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>